vivaldi.net 2018-12-29

# Privacy Policy | Vivaldi Community

## General

At Vivaldi Technologies AS (“Vivaldi”), protecting your privacy is one of our top priorities. We strictly protect the security of your personal information within Vivaldi’s websites. We do not share or sell your data with any third party. We protect user data from disclosure, with exceptions only requested by law or court order.

## Types of data we collect and for what  purposes

When you visit Vivaldi’s websites, we collect some visitor statistics. The visitor statistics include information about the visitor’s IP-address, usage patterns, the point in time the visitor visits our websites on Vivaldi.net and Vivaldi.com and information about the browser and operating system the visitor uses.

This information is collected solely for statistical purpose and is not used to identify individuals. We use these statistics to improve and optimize usability of our products and services for our users. These statistics help us determine where we need to improve and prioritize our resources.

Vivaldi’s websites use cookies. A cookie is a tiny data file that resides on your computer, mobile phone or another device, and allows us to recognize you as a visitor when you return to the website using the same computer and web browser. This allows us to provide more customized experience to our visitors. You can remove or block cookies using the settings in your browser.

We keep the contact information you provide in your account profile. We use this contact information in case of lost passwords, username recovery, account confirmation, or other account-related support work.

Vivaldi’s websites use a modified version of the [Akismet](https://akismet.com/wordpress/) plugin to mitigate spam. The plugin has been modified so as not to send personal information to the service. The only information we send to Akismet is username and content of posts. Akismet’s Privacy Policy can be viewed [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/).

## Access

Vivaldi has strict restrictions on access to user data. Only a limited number of Vivaldi’s employees or employees at Vivaldi’s service providers for the web hosting services have access to such data.

## Transfer

Vivaldi cooperates with [Advania](http://www.advania.com/datacentres/) data centers for the hosting and running of the Vivaldi websites. Advania data centers will process and handle personal data on Vivaldi’s behalf in accordance with this Privacy Statement, and in accordance with applicable laws and regulations. Vivaldi will not transfer any personal data to any third party except as required by law or law enforcement.

## Retention and deletion

Vivaldi will delete personal information when all purposes of the personal information processing have been fulfilled and when deletion is allowed pursuant to applicable laws and regulations.

### Vivaldi Mail Policies

By obtaining a Vivaldi.net account, you are entitled to use the Vivaldi Mail service.

As a condition of your use of Vivaldi Mail, you agree to abide by all applicable local, state, national and international laws and regulations and adhere to the guidelines below.

#### Spam and bulk email

  * Your Vivaldi Mail account will not be used to distribute spam or unsolicited commercial emails.
  * It is prohibited to use Vivaldi Mail to send emails which violates the CAN-SPAM Act or other anti-spam laws; to send unauthorized emails via open, third-party servers; or to distribute the email addresses of any person without their consent.
  * Automation of the Vivaldi Mail interface is also not allowed. This means that you cannot send, delete or filter emails in a manner that misleads or deceives users.
  * Also, keep in mind that your definition of “unsolicited” or “unwanted” email may differ from your email recipients’ perception. Use your best judgement when sending emails to a large number of recipients in Vivaldi Mail. Even if the recipients elected to receive emails from you in the past that does not mean the current mail campaign is welcome.
  * When a Vivaldi Mail user marks an email as spam, it increases the likelihood that future messages that you send will also be classified as spam by the spam filter that we use and run locally.

#### Malware

You will not use Vivaldi Mail to knowingly transmit or upload any material that contains viruses, trojan horses, worms, time bombs, cancelbots, or any other harmful or deleterious programs. In addition, you will not distribute content that harms or interferes with the operation of networks, servers or other infrastructure belonging to Vivaldi or others.

#### Fraud, phishing and other deceptive practices

Unless you have their explicit permission, you will not access another user’s Vivaldi Mail account.

Don’t use Vivaldi Mail to trick, mislead or deceive other users into sharing information under false pretences.

Don’t phish for users’ data, such as login information, passwords, financial details or identification numbers, or use Vivaldi Mail as part of a scheme to defraud others.

#### Child safety

Vivaldi has a zero-tolerance policy against child sexual abuse imagery. If we become aware of such content, we will report it to the Norwegian Police Department, as required by law. We may also take disciplinary action, including termination, against the Vivaldi Mail accounts of those involved.

#### Copyright

You will respect copyright laws in your use of Vivaldi Mail and will not infringe on the intellectual property rights of others, including patent, trademark, trade secret or other proprietary rights.

You are also not allowed to encourage or induce others to violate intellectual property rights. You can report copyright infringement to Vivaldi by using [this form](https://vivaldi.com/contact/).

#### Harassment

You will not use Vivaldi Mail to harass, intimidate or threaten others. Anyone found to be using Vivaldi Mail for these purposes may have their account disabled.

#### Illegal activity

Keep it legal. Don’t use Vivaldi Mail to promote, organize or engage in unlawful activities.

#### Message storage, file storage, outbound messages and other limitations

The amount of storage space per user is limited. Some sent or received messages, or uploaded or downloaded files, may not be processed due to space constraints or other limitations. You agree that Vivaldi is not responsible or liable for the deletion or failure to store messages, files or other information.

### Policy enforcement

You can report abuse by using [our contact form](https://vivaldi.com/contact/). Vivaldi may disable accounts that are found to be in violation of these policies. If your account is disabled, and you believe that it was a mistake, please contact us by using [this form](https://vivaldi.com/contact/).

## Reviews

Procedures are reviewed regularly to ensure that the policies are followed. Any non-conformance regarding the policies will be corrected without unnecessary delay.

## Updates and changes

This Privacy Statement may be updated or changed. When we post changes to this Privacy Statement, we will include the date when the Privacy Statement was last updated. If there are material changes to this statement or in how we use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification.

## Contact information

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, or privacy on our websites, please drop us a line at [vivaldi.com/contact](https://vivaldi.com/contact).

Last modified and effective: April 19, 2018.

## Revision History
